patsnap.com 2018-01-15

# Privacy Policy and Terms of Use | PatSnap

## Introduction

PatSnap Pte. Ltd. (“PatSnap”, “we”) operates patsnap.com. It is PatSnap's policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our website, products and services (“ **Services** ”).

Here at PatSnap, we pride ourselves on customer confidentiality. This Privacy Policy contains everything you need to know regarding any collection, use, storage and disclosure of information or data in the course of your use of PatSnap’s Services. Information or data collection can come in two (2) main forms. Firstly, in the form of non-personally identifying information or data that does not directly or indirectly identify you (“ **Non-Personally Identifying Data** ”). Secondly, in the form of personally identifying information or data that on its own or in combination with other information or data can be used to identify you (“ **Personally Identifying Data** ”).

By your use of the Services, you are consenting to the collection, use and storage of your information as set out in this Privacy Policy.

Although most changes are likely to be minor, PatSnap may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and at PatSnap’s sole discretion. PatSnap encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any changes are made shall imply that you are aware of the changes in this Privacy Policy and shall constitute your deemed acceptance of such changes.

## 1\. Data Collection

Like most website operators, PatSnap collects Non-Personally-Identifying Data of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, including but not limited to browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. PatSnap’s purpose in collecting Non-Personally Identifying Data is to better understand how PatSnap’s visitors use its website. From time to time, PatSnap may release Non-Personally-Identifying Data in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

PatSnap also collects potentially Personally-Identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. PatSnap does not use such information to identify its visitors save for the manner and circumstances as described below.

## 2\. What happens to any data that we collect

Certain Services require PatSnap to gather Personally-Identifying Data (“the **Interaction** ”). The amount and type of information that PatSnap gathers depends on the nature of the Interaction. Certain Interactions require you to provide additional information, including as necessary, the personal and financial information required to effect an Interaction. In each case, PatSnap collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s Interaction with PatSnap. PatSnap does not disclose Personally-Identifying Data save for the circumstances as identified in Clause 3, 4 and 5. Visitors can always refuse to supply Personally-Identifying Data, however it may prevent them from accessing certain Services.

## 3\. Sharing your personal data for legal and business purposes

Important note: For the provision of Services, we may be required to share your information with other parties, including but not limited to, financial institutions, and PatSnap affiliates. We will always only share the limited personal information to that which is strictly required in each unique Interaction. You agree and consent that Personally Identifying Data may be shared with the above stated parties as set out in this Clause 3.

## 4\. Anonymous Statistics

We may anonymise your Non-Personally Identifying Data and Personally Identifying Data for the purposes of internal statistics (“ **the Reports** ”) for example product research to help us improve our Services. All information disclosed in the Reports shall only include Non-Personally Identifying data or anonymised data. We may in turn pass these Reports onto third parties.

## 5\. Marketing Communications

From time to time you may receive from us a variety of communications, including but not limited to newsletters, emails and text messages (“ **the Marking Communications** ”), that will include service updates, product advertising and offers related to our Services which we believe you may be interested in.

At any time, you may change your Marketing Communication preferences, either by:

\- Electing to unsubscribe from the Marketing Communications sent to you by following the ‘unsubscribe’ link which can be found at the bottom of the emails

\- Contacting our team directly using the ‘Contact Us’ option, found either in the email we sent or on the Patsnap.com website.

Aside from Marketing Communication, please note that from time to time, you may receive some important service information that we believe is critical to the use of our Services. In these exceptional circumstances, such information will be sent to you regardless of your Marketing Communication preferences.

If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users.

## 6\. Security & location of data

PatSnap may disclose Personally-Identifying Data to its employees, contractors and affiliated organisations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on PatSnap’s behalf or to provide the Services; and (ii) have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organisations may be located outside of Singapore; by using PatSnap’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Any Personally Identifying Data sent to any location outside Singapore will be afforded the same or equivalent protection as required by the Personal Data Protection Act 2012 (“PDPA”). PatSnap will not rent or sell Personally-Identifying Data to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organisations, as described above, PatSnap discloses Personally-Identifying Data and Personally-Identifying Information only when required to do so and to the extent required by Singapore law. PatSnap takes all measures reasonably necessary in accordance with the PDPA to protect against the unauthorised access, use, alteration or destruction of Personally-Identifying Data.

Patsnap will only keep your Personally Identifying Data for as long as it is necessary to provide you with the Services and to comply with governmental regulations. If you wish to terminate your use of the Services with Patsnap and would like to withdraw your consent to allow us to collect, use and store the Personally Identifying Data, please email us and we will take the necessary steps to delete said data in due course.

## 7\. Cookies

Patsnap may place and access certain cookies on computer of visitors. PatSnap uses cookies to help PatSnap identify and track visitors, their usage of PatSnap website, and their website access preferences. The use of cookies helps to improve the efficacy of Patsnap’s services. PatSnap visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers can choose to delete the cookies at any time by setting their browsers to refuse cookies before using PatSnap’s websites. However, please note that certain features of PatSnap's websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

## 8\. Children Under 13

Patsnap Services are not directed to children under the age of thirteen (13). Patsnap does not knowingly collect Personally-Identifying Data without the consent of a parent or legal guardian. If a child below the age of 13 is found to be using Patsnap Services, and Personally-Identifying Data has been transmitted to us Patsnap shall take the necessary steps to remove the Personally-Identifying Data collected and terminate the Patsnap Services provided.

## 9\. Access to your data and your rights

At any time during your PatSnap subscription, you can request the right to access information regarding the Patsnap’s process of use and disclosure of Non-Personally Identifying Data and Personally-Identifying Data at any time. We will provide all the information at no additional cost to you.

## Contact Us

If you have any concerns or questions with any of the terms within the privacy policy that you have just read, please do not hesitate to get in touch with our team at [support@patsnap.com](mailto:support@patsnap.com) and we will be able to answer any questions you might have.

This Privacy Policy was last updated in March 2016.

Note: Our Privacy Policy (and our Terms of Use) has been derived from the privacy policy of the generous team at Wordpress.com, who has shared their Privacy Policy under a Creative Commons Sharealike license. This text is also shared under a Creative Commons Sharealike license, and we would direct you to the original if you would like to reuse the content you read here.
